### Experian Global Sites

Search 

* Client Sign in

* [Customer  
    Acquisition](https://www.experian.com/business-services/customer-acquisition)
    * [Customer  
        Acquisition](https://www.experian.com/business-services/customer-acquisition)
* [Customer  
    Management](https://www.experian.com/business-services/customer-management)
    * [Customer  
        Management](https://www.experian.com/business-services/customer-management)
* [Risk  
    Management](https://www.experian.com/business-services/risk-management)
    * [Risk  
        Management](https://www.experian.com/business-services/risk-management)
* [Fraud  
    Management](https://www.experian.com/business-services/fraud-management)
    * [Fraud  
        Management](https://www.experian.com/business-services/fraud-management)
* [Debt  
    Recovery](https://www.experian.com/business-services/debt-recovery)
    * [Debt  
        Recovery](https://www.experian.com/business-services/debt-recovery)
* [Consulting  
    Services](https://www.experian.com/consulting-services/index)
    * [Consulting  
        Services](https://www.experian.com/consulting-services/index)
* [Regulatory  
    Compliance](https://www.experian.com/decision-analytics/financial-services-compliance)
    * [Regulatory  
        Compliance](https://www.experian.com/decision-analytics/financial-services-compliance)
* [Thought  
    Leadership](https://www.experian.com/innovation/thought-leadership)
    * [Thought  
        Leadership](https://www.experian.com/innovation/thought-leadership)

* Solutions
* Industries
* Specialized Services

* Automotive
* Health
* Business Credit
* Workforce Management
* Other

* Automotive
* Health
* Business Credit
* Workforce Management
* Other

### Client Login

Privacy at Experian
===================

Experian is committed to providing consumers with the notice, choice, and education about the use of their personal information in today’s world.

1. [Privacy](https://www.experian.com/privacy) 
2. index 

Privacy Policies
----------------

### Consumer Policies

We want you to be familiar with Experian’s privacy practices relating to our consumer products and services.

### Business Policies

View Experian’s privacy practices relating to our business-to-business services and products.

Experian Global Data Principles
-------------------------------

Our five Global Data Principles embody these key values (see below). They guide how we manage and use data, build products and conduct our business around the world. These principles apply to all our data, in all our businesses, and in every country. We developed the principles to better reflect our commitments to individuals, businesses, clients, and the public, which have advanced as market demands and expectations have evolved.

### Security

Data security is critical. Securing and protecting data against unauthorised access, use, disclosure, and loss are key priorities for us.

### Accuracy

We will make data as accurate, complete, and relevant as possible for the manner in which it is used, always in compliance with legal requirements.

### Fairness

We collect and use data fairly and for legitimate purposes, balancing privacy expectations with the social and economic benefits derived from the responsible use of data for individuals, businesses and clients.

### Transparency

We are open and transparent about the types of data we collect, where we get it, how it is used and where it is shared. Where appropriate we provide individuals with access to the data we collect about them and the ability to correct, restrict or delete data.

### Inclusion

We seek to improve financial health and inclusion for all through the innovative use of relevant data to help individuals improve their financial lives.

Approach to Privacy
-------------------

Experian® considers itself a steward of the information it collects, maintains and utilizes. Our responsibility is to ensure the security of the information in our care and to maintain the privacy of consumers through appropriate, responsible use.  
  
We provide services based on information about millions of individuals and businesses. Use of that data is guided by our Global Data Principles. Our Global Data Principles embody our key values and are used as a framework to guide how we manage and use data, build products and conduct our business around the world.

Data policies, built on our principles, more specifically define how that information may be used. The policies vary to meet the legal requirements and consumer expectations in the area in which the information product or service is being used.  
  
Underlying these policies is Experian's commitment to provide consumers notice, choice and education about the use of personal information. Educated consumers are better equipped to be effective, successful participants in a world that increasingly relies on the exchange of information to efficiently deliver the products and services consumers demand.  
  
Today, our business clients' needs, and consumers' expectations are constantly changing, and technology is constantly evolving. Our approach to privacy, rooted in the Global Data Principles, enables Experian to respond to those constantly changing needs and expectations and provides the flexibility to implement new processes and policies to resolve information issues in this dynamic environment.

Residents of specific states have certain rights with respect to personal information collected and processed under state privacy laws.  You may exercise the following rights, subject to certain exceptions and limitations:

* Right to Know/Access: You have a right to know and access the personal information that Experian maintains about them.
* Right to Delete: You have the right to request deletion of the personal information Experian has obtained or maintains about you, subject to certain exceptions.
* Right to Correct: You have the right to request correction of inaccurate personal information that Experian maintains about you.
* Right to Opt-Out: You have the right to exercise control over the processing of certain personal information.  This may include the right to opt-out from the sale, sharing, processing, and use of personal information for sales, certain profiling or targeted advertising, and from the use of sensitive personal information.
* Right to Opt-Out or Limit the Use of Sensitive Personal Information: Residents of certain states have the right to opt-out or limit the use or disclosure of sensitive personal information that Experian has collected or maintains about them.  Opting-out includes the consumer's right to limit generation, use, and disclosure of sensitive personal information about them.
* Right to Non-Discrimination: You have the right not to be discriminated against for exercising any of your consumer rights granted by applicable state privacy laws.
* Right to Portability: You have the right to obtain a copy of personal information Experian maintains about you in a format that is portable and readily usable.
* Right to Appeal: You have the right to appeal Experian's decision regarding the consumer's request.  In order to appeal a declined request, please email optout@experian.com

In order to exercise your rights through our online privacy portal, please click the link below:

To learn more about your rights stated above, please see our [U.S. Consumer Data Privacy Policy](https://www.experian.com/privacy/us-consumer-data-privacy-policy "U.S. Consumer Data Privacy Policy")  
  
Please note that you may have additional rights under state and federal laws separate from your rights under the U.S. Consumer Data Privacy Policy. Those laws include the Fair Credit Reporting Act, the Gramm-Leach Bliley Act, the Driver’s Privacy Protection Act, and the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act. The protections provided by those laws are separate from your rights under the U.S. Consumer Data Privacy Policy and may apply in place of some of the rights under the U.S. Consumer Data Privacy Policy.

You may learn about your rights relating to your Experian credit data [here](https://www.experian.com/blogs/ask-experian/credit-education/report-basics/fair-credit-reporting-act-fcra/#s3 "Visit                     Experian's Summary of Rights page"). To obtain a copy of your Experian credit report, please go to [https://www.annualcreditreport.com/index.action](https://www.annualcreditreport.com/index.action "annual credit report page")

NOTE:  This section is not designed for inquiries related to an individual's credit report.

If you would like to order a copy of your personal credit report or your credit score or for fraud assistance, we offer the following fast and efficient service options:

Online: Go to [Personal Services](https://www.experian.com/consumer-products/free-credit-report.html "Personal Services") and select any of our options for ordering your personal credit report.  
By Phone: Contact Experian's National Consumer Assistance Center at 1 888 EXPERIAN (1 888 397 3742).

If you already have an Experian credit report you can [dispute your information online](https://www.experian.com/disputes/main.html). Or, contact us at the phone number on your report. We cannot accept disputes via email.

For questions about your credit monitoring membership, please visit our [contact us page](https://www.experian.com/contact/personal-services-contacts.html).

If you have any questions about Experian's approach to privacy or any of its specific privacy policies, please write to us at:

Chief Privacy Officer  
Compliance Department  
Experian  
475 Anton Blvd.  
Costa Mesa, CA 92626

Consumer Privacy Policies
-------------------------

Applying individualized collection strategies will help your organization meet regulatory requirements that call for fair consumer treatments.

Opting Out
----------

The below information applies to consumers in the United States of America. If you are a consumer in the United Kingdom, please visit [Experian’s UK Consumer Information portal](https://www.experian.co.uk/privacy/privacy-policies "Experian UK Consumer Information portal").

If you are a consumer from the United States of America and are looking to take actions related to your credit data such as, receive your credit report, place your credit on hold, etc. please visit [experian.com/consumer](https://www.experian.com/consumer "Experian Consumer website").

[Exercise your consumer data rights with Experian (opt-out and others)](#)

You can choose to opt-out of the sale of your personal information and data, opt out of processing your data for targeted advertising, and limit the use of your sensitive information. This is not related to your credit report, and will not affect your credit score.

To request opt-out, deletion, a copy of, or to correct your data please visit our [privacy portal](https://consumerprivacy.experian.com/). 

If you prefer to submit your request via phone you may contact Experian at: 833-210-4615

If you prefer to submit a written request, please mail your request to the following address:

Experian  
PO Box 703  
Allen, TX 75013

[Learn how to submit more broadly applicable requests with industry groups.](#)

**Opting Out  
**For more information on opting out of specific types of targeted advertising, click on the applicable link below:

* [Opting Out of Preapproved Offers](https://www.optoutprescreen.com/ "Opting Out of Preapproved Offers"): _This link will take you directly to OptOutPrescreen.com, which is the official Consumer Credit Reporting Industry website to accept and process requests from consumers to Opt-In or Opt-Out of firm offers of credit or insurance._
* **Experian Membership Marketing Opt-Out:** _If you are an Experian member, please log into your Experian account and manage your communication preferences._
* To opt out of Experian’s affiliate Tapad, please go here [https://crportal.tapad.com/#/](https://crportal.tapad.com/#/)

Experian may periodically change its privacy policies as new products and services are offered or as its existing products and services evolve to meet customer needs. Privacy policies are typically dated to reflect the most recent update.

Recent updates to any Experian U.S. privacy policy will be posted to this section.

**Updated:February 9, 2023**

Removed Data Select Policy due to decomissioning of the product

**Updated: February 28, 2023**

ConsumerInfo.com, Inc. Policy

**Updated: July 7, 2022**

CCPA Privacy Policy

**Updated: November 18, 2021**

CSID Privacy Policy

**Updated: March 1, 2019**

Updated the U.S.- EU Privacy Shield Privacy Policy to include the application of the policy to the United Kingdom.

**Updated: October 15, 2018**

Modified URL link for the independent dispute resolution mechanism in the U.S.- EU Privacy Shield Privacy Policy.

**Updated: May 15, 2018**

Experian U.S.- EU Privacy Shield Privacy Policy added to the Experian.com website.

**Updated: June 17, 2015**

Updated Hitwise Privacy Policy to now include information about data collected through partnerships.

**Updated: May 14, 2015**

Updated Opting Out page and subpages Direct Mail and Telemarketing to now include information on online advertising and introduced a new page, Request Experian Marketing Data Report.

**Updated: August 26, 2011**

Experian ConnectSM

**Updated: October 16, 2009**

The AutoCount privacy policy.

**Updated: January 28, 2009**

The Experian Small Business privacy policy was added.  

**Updated: October 31, 2008**

The AutoCount privacy policy.  

**Updated: July 22, 2007**

The Online Personal Credit Reports policy was updated.  

**Updated: July 18, 2007**

Autocheck privacy policy updated integrating commercial and consumer policies and enhancements to non-personal information uses.  

**Updated: June 8, 2007**

The AutoCount consumer privacy policy was added.  

**Updated: January 20, 2006**

The AutoCheck consumer privacy policy has been updated. Changes include revisions to the Information Collection and Uses section, and the addition of information on how Experian uses Web site 'cookies'. Web Log Information has also been replaced with the Web site Analysis section which further defines our Web site measurement practices.

**Updated: July 1, 2004**

In the "Permission email" section, language was updated to outline how email addresses are shared and used.

The AutoCheck® Vehicle History Report privacy policy has been updated.

Contact information for questions regarding the privacy policy was updated.

**Updated: August 28, 2003**

The Auto Prospect Online privacy policy was added.

**Updated: June 12, 2003**

The AutoCheck privacy policy was updated for consumers, and a privacy policy for commercial users has been created. In each, Experian identifies the use of a credit card processing company. In the commercial, Experian retains the commercial users' credit card information for billing purposes only.

**Updated: March 11, 2003**

The Online Personal Credit Reports policy was updated to state that information other than credit report information may be used for authentication.

**Updated: March 7, 2003**

ePIN+ is a Web-based relational database system for reporting relevant delivery status about a piece of mail as it moves through the U.S. Postal Service® delivery network, either on its way to a consumer's mailbox, or from an individual delivery point back to a remittance or other service facility.

**Updated: February 26, 2003**

Within the U.S. section of www.experian.com Web logs and cookies are used to collect aggregated statistics about Web site visitors so that we can better understand what areas of our Web site are of interest to you. This technology does not track any individually identifiable information, but rather records your Web site visit anonymously.

**Updated: February 10, 2003**

The Opting out of Direct Mail and Opting out of Telemarketing sections of Experian's privacy policy were updated to reflect a new telephone number to contact Experian.

**Updated: October 23, 2002**

Experian's product and service privacy section of our U.S. Web site was updated to add a privacy policy description for business-to-business Internet client registration. This application is for new and current subscribers serviced by Experian Information Solutions, Inc.

**Updated: September 26, 2002**

Experian's product and service privacy section of our U.S. Web site was updated to add a privacy policy description for List Link ExpressSM and List Link AdvancedSM business-to-business online prospecting tools of Experian Marketing Solutions, Inc.

**Updated: March 8, 2002**

Experian's Product and service privacy policies section of our U.S. Web site was updated to add a privacy policy description for AutoCheck, Experian's comprehensive vehicle history report service. Please visit our AutoCheck privacy policy for more information.

Experian is a non-exclusive Full Service Provider Licensee of the USPS®. The prices established for these products are not established, controlled, or approved by the U.S. Government or the USPS. The following trademarks are owned by the USPS: U.S. Postal Service®

Experian Privacy Policies
-------------------------

Experian provides a number of information products and services to both businesses and consumers online. Because the collection and use of personally identifiable information may vary among the products and services available on Experian's Web sites, at any point where personally identifiable information is collected, Experian provides notices that explain:

**What information is being collected  
**How the information may be used  
What choices you have regarding the collection and use of the information  
The notices are clearly posted, either at the point of collection or through an easily identifiable link at the point of collection.

**Policy Details  
**Experian may periodically change its privacy policies as new products and services are offered or as its existing products and services evolve to meet customer needs. Privacy policies are typically dated to reflect the most recent update. To review Updates to Experian's privacy policies, visit the Recent Updates section.

* Industries

* Solutions and Services

* Data

* Additional Resources

* Blogs

EXPERIAN'S DIVERSITY, EQUITY AND INCLUSION [Learn more how Experian is committed](https://www.experian.com/diversity/)

DATA PRIVACY [Your privacy choices](https://consumerprivacy.experian.com/)

©2024 Experian Information Solutions, Inc. All rights reserved.

Experian and the Experian trademarks used herein are trademarks or registered trademarks of Experian. Other product or company names mentioned herein are the property of their respective owners.
